Preliminary Guide to the John Tate Lanning papers, 1926-1976
Duke University. University Archives
John Tate Lanning papers 1926-1976
Lanning, John Tate, 1902-
36 linear feet Extent: 24,000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
John Tate Lanning (1902-1976) was a historian, colonial Latin America scholar, and Duke University Professor of History. This collection includes correspondence, manuscript materials, committee notes, student papers, newsletters, conference materials, curriculum materials, travel diaries, interview transcriptions, and field research notes. Major subjects include the Duke University Department of History, Duke University Research Council, Hispanic American Historical Review, Latin American library resources, student and teaching of Latin American history, research in the social sciences, and Latin American colleges and universities. English.
UA.29.02.0036
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
Gift; 1977; 77-40.
Gift; 1978; 78-76.
Biographical Note
John Tate Lanning was born in Linwood, N.C. in 1902. He received degrees from Trinity College (A.B., 1924) and the University of California (A.M., 1925, Ph.D., 1928).
A teacher, lecturer, educator, and historian, Lanning began his career at Duke University in 1927. In 1942, he became a full professor, and became a James B. Duke professor in 1961. He was one of the first Guggenheim Fellows in the early 1930s and won several research awards in the field of history. In 1955, Lanning won the Carnegie Fund Prize for his manuscript, The 18th Century Enlightenment in the University of Can Carlos de Guatemala.
Lanning was the managing editor of the Hispanic American Historical Review (1939-1945) and held memberships in the American Historical Association, Phi Beta Kappa, and the Sociedad de Geografia e Historia de Guatemala. He specialized in colonial Hispanic-American history and wrote The Spanish Missions of Georgia (1935) and 10 other works.
A self-proclaimed bibliophile, Lanning regarded the Duke University's Perkins Library as the heart of the university. He was instrumental in developing Perkins Library's book collection on Hispanic America. Upon his death, Lanning was honored with three book funds established in his name: one by the Hanes Foundation of Winston-Salem, N.C. and the other two by his students.
Lanning married Elizabeth B. Williams in 1932 and died in Durham, N.C., on August 15, 1976.
Collection Overview
Contains personal and professional papers relating to John Tate Lanning's career as an educator, historian, and scholar of Latin American history. Types of materials include correspondence, manuscript materials, committee notes, student papers, newsletters, conference materials, curriculum materials, travel diaries, interview transcripts, and field research notes. Includes materials pertaining to Lanning's editorship of the Hispanic-American Historical Review, interactions with the journal's managing editors, Duke University's Research Council, and the Lanning family. Also contains a diary Lanning kept during a research trip in England, Spain, and France, 1926 October-1927 May. Materials range in date from 1926-1976.
Items are arranged into several alphabetical files, which have been loosely interfiled to preserve original order of the collection.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Dept. of History -- Faculty; Duke University. Research Council; Hispanic American historical review; Latin America -- History -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Learning and scholarship -- Latin America; Lanning, John Tate, 1902-; Latin America -- Library resources; Latin America -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- North Carolina; Social sciences -- Research -- North Carolina -- Durham; Universities and colleges -- Latin America
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Container List:
  - AB-ADL (Box 1)
  - ADL-ALD (Box 1)
  - ALE-AMB (Box 1)
  - AME-ANS (Box 1)
  - ANT-ARI (Box 1)
  - ARM-AZU (Box 1)
  - Addy, George (Box 1)
  - Advisees (Box 1)
  - Agfa Ansco Corporation (Box 1)
  - Aiton, Arthur S. (Box 1)
  - Alden, John (Box 1)
  - Alliance for Progress, [3 folders] (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 1)
  - American Catholic Historical Association (Box 1)
  - American Historical Association, [2 folders]
    - Beveridge Award (Box 1)
    - Hispanics (Box 1)
    - Nominating Committee, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - American Historical Review (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Association (Box 1)
  - Anna, Timothy (Box 1)
  - Archives (Latin-American), Letters in answer to questionnaire (Box 1)
  - Application, Aid in Publication of Dissertation (Box 1)
  - Appointments Office, Recommendations (Box 1)
  - Archivo General de Indias (Box 1)
  - Indices and Inventories of the Archivo General de Indias (Box 1)
  - Arocha, Senor Don Manuel (Box 1)
  - Arteaga, Beatriz (Box 1)
  - Ashby, Labor Theory of the Mexican Revolution under Lazaro Cardenas (Box 1)
  - Auxier, Goerge W. (Box 1)
  - BAB-BAN (Box 2)
  - BAB-BAN (Box 2)
  - BAR-BEA (Box 2)
  - BEC-BER (Box 2)
  - BET-BLA (Box 2)
  - BLI-BOR (Box 2)
  - BOS-BRI (Box 2)
  - BRO-BUL (Box 2)
  - BUN-BYR (Box 2)
  - Bailey, Thomas A. (Box 2)
  - Baker, George T. (Box 2)
  - Baker, Maury (Box 2)
  - Bauzon, Leslie (Box 2)
  - Baxter, Joseph R. (Box 2)
  - Bemis, Samuel Flagg (Box 2)
  - Bestor, Arthur (Box 2)
  - Bettersworth, John Knox (Box 2)
  - Beveridge Memorial Fund (Box 2)
  - Bierck, Harold A. (Box 2)
  - Blossom, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Bolton, Herbert E. (Box 2)
  - Books, Circulars and Catalogs (Box 2)
  - Books, General Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Books, E. Iturriaga y Cia, F. Schwab (Box 2)
  - Books Ordered (Box 2)
  - Boone Memorial (Box 2)
  - Bornman, Mary Elizabeth (Box 2)
  - Boyd, W.K. (Box 2)
  - Branscomb, Harvie, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - Brice, Ashbel (Box 2)
  - Brinkley, Florence (Box 2)
  - Brown, Milton P. (Box 2)
  - Brown, Thomas A. (Box 2)
  - Bullock, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Bumgartner, Louis (Box 2)
  - Burke, Michael E. (Box 2)
  - Burkholder, Mark A. (Box 3)
  - CAB-CAP (Box 3)
  - CAR-CAS (Box 3)
  - CAT-CHA (Box 3)
  - CHE-CHU (Box 3)
  - CIR-COE (Box 3)
  - COK-COM (Box 3)
  - COM-COS (Box 3)
  - COT-CRO (Box 3)
  - CRU-CYK (Box 3)
  - Calkins, Robert D. (Box 3)
  - Calvo Serer, Rafael (Box 3)
  - Campbell, John Wilson (Box 3)
  - Canavan, Francis P. (Box 3)
  - Candler, Frances G. (Box 3)
  - Caracas Project (Box 3)
  - Cardozo, Manoel (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Foundation, Duke Grants in Aid Program (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Revolving Fund Award, The Enlightenment (Box 3)
  - Cartter, Dean Allan (Box 3)
  - Casimes, Mary (Box 3)
  - Castaneda, Carlos E., [2 folders] (Box 3)
  - Catalog of Lanning's Library, [3 folders] (Box 3)
  - Caughey, John of Pacific Historical Review (Box 3)
  - Cedulas, University of Mexico, [2 folders] (Box 3)
  - Cedulas, University of San Carolos of Guatemala (Box 3)
  - Chamberlain, Robert S. (Box 3)
  - Chan, Shan Wing (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Dewitt S. (Box 3)
  - Chapman, Charles E. (Box 3)
  - Chicago Press (Box 3)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 3)
  - Cintron-Rios, Maria (Box 3)
  - Clark, Chester W. (Box 3)
  - Class Rolls, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Cline, Howard (Box 3)
  - Clyde, Paul (Box 3)
  - Coggins, W.J. (Box 3)
  - Cole, R. Taylor (Box 3)
  - Committee onCultural Relations (Box 3)
  - Committee on International Studies (Box 3)
  - Committee on Publication (Box 3)
  - Conference on Latin American History, [5 folders] (Box 4)
  - Conference on Latin American History, Constitution Revision (Box 4)
  - Conference on Latin American History, Current, [4 folders] (Box 4)
  - Consulates (Box 4)
  - Consulates of the U.S. in Latin America (Box 4)
  - Coordinate Board (Box 4)
  - Copyright (Box 4)
  - Corbitt, D.C. (Box 4)
  - Cornell University and Carnegie Revolving Fund (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Press (Box 4)
  - Correspondence re: Lanning's last illness and letters of condolence (Box 4)
  - Cortazar, Roberto (Box 4)
  - Couch, Leon (Box 4)
  - Coulter, E. Merton (Box 4)
  - Council on Hispanic Research (Box 5)
    - General materials, [8 folders] (Box 5)
    - Library Project (Box 5)
    - General Business (Box 5)
    - Applications (Box 5)
    - Budget (Box 5)
    - Constitution (Box 5)
    - Del Valle Library (Box 5)
    - Esso Conference (Box 5)
    - Exchange Students (Box 5)
    - Garnica Silva, Antonio (Box 5)
    - Exchange Students (Box 5)
    - Luzon, Jose M. (Box 5)
    - Exchange Students (Box 5)
    - Sanchez Mantero, Rafael (Box 5)
    - Exchange Students (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Funds (Box 5)
    - Minutes, [2 folders] (Box 5)
    - New Black Legend (Box 5)
    - Follow-up (Box 5)
    - Organizations (Box 5)
    - Publications and Subsidies (Box 5)
    - Publications and Subsidies (Box 5)
    - Statement of Purpose (Box 5)
    - Visiting Professor (Box 5)
    - Wardropper, Bruce (Box 5)
  - Cox, I.J. (Box 5)
  - Criticisms (Box 5)
  - Crum, Lewis (Box 5)
  - Cumberland, Charles C. (Box 5)
  - Curtiss, John S. (Box 5)
  - DAL-DAV (Box 5)
  - DAV-DEN (Box 5)
  - DEP-DOB (Box 5)
  - DOC-DUJ (Box 5)
  - DUK-DUL (Box 5)
  - DUM-DUT (Box 5)
  - Dale, William Pratt (Box 5)
  - De Conde, Alexander (Box 5)
  - D'Eca, Raul (Box 5)
  - Department of State (Box 5)
  - Diffie, Bailey (Box 5)
  - Doherty, Mary Louis (Box 5)
  - Doherty Fellowship Recommendations (Box 5)
  - Donoso (Box 5)
  - Duke University Faculty Bylaws Committee, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Duke University Graduate School and Council (Box 5)
  - Duke University Library (Box 5)
  - Duke University Press (Box 5)
  - Duke University Faculty Senate (Box 5)
  - Dunbar Temple, Ella (Box 5)
  - Dwire, H.R. (Box 5)
  - EAG-ELL (Box 6)
  - ELP-ENG (Box 6)
  - ENR-EZQ (Box 6)
  - Easterby, J.H. (Box 6)
  - Edens, Hollis (Box 6)
  - Editors, Historical Reviews Espinosa, J. Manuel (Box 6)
  - "Even a Professor" (Box 6)
  - Examinations (Box 6)
  - Extramural Activities (Box 6)
  - FAB-FER (Box 6)
  - FER-FLE (Box 6)
  - FLO-FOX (Box 6)
  - FRA-FUR (Box 6)
  - Fals-Borda (Box 6)
  - Fein, John (Box 6)
  - Few, William P. (Box 6)
  - Flick, Carlos Thomas (Box 6)
  - Fondo de Cultura Economica (Box 6)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 6)
  - Foundations, Fellowships (Box 6)
  - Foundations, Publication Proposals to Forin, Eida Martellozzo, [2 folders] (Box 6)
  - Friede, Juan (Box 6)
  - Fulbright Scholarships (Box 6)
  - Fulbright Screening Committee (Box 6)
  - GAG-GAU (Box 6)
  - GAV-GOE (Box 6)
  - GOH-GRA (Box 6)
  - GRA-GUE (Box 6)
  - GUI-GUZ (Box 6)
  - Gandara (Box 6)
  - "Gauld-Percival Farquhar and the Cuba Railroad, 1900-1903"" (Box 6)
  - Geiger, Maynard (Box 6)
  - Gervin, Spencer (Box 6)
  - Gibson, Charles (Box 6)
  - Gil, Carlos (Box 6)
  - Gilbert, Allan H. (Box 6)
  - Gilber, Katherine (Box 6)
  - Gillin, John (Box 6)
  - Graduate School (Box 7)
    - Applications (Box 7)
    - Correspondence with Dean of Graduate School (Box 7)
    - General information (Box 7)
    - Long-Range Planning Subcommittee 1958-1961 (Box 7)
    - Long-Range Planning Subcommittee, Report (Box 7)
    - Long-Range Planning Subcommittee, Reports (Box 7)
    - Publications
      - Abert, James G. (Box 7)
      - Baird, Charles O., 1964 (Box 7)
      - Barlow, Norman, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Charudhri, M.A., 1964 (Box 7)
      - Dallmayr, Winifried, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Duly, Leslie, 1965 (Box 7)
      - Goff, Richard (Box 7)
      - Gossett, Louise, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Halloran, William F., 1965 (Box 7)
      - Heggoy, Alf A., 1963 (Box 7)
      - Howell, John, 1963 (Box 7)
      - Katzenmeyer, W.G., 1963 (Box 7)
      - Hudgins, H.C., 1966 (Box 7)
      - Lentriccia, W.H., 1966 (Box 7)
      - Lloyd, Peter J., 1962 (Box 7)
      - Martin, David, 1962 (Box 7)
      - Mathews, Jane Dehart, 1966 (Box 7)
      - Pittillo, Robert, 1962 (Box 7)
      - Porter, Earl W., 1961 (Box 7)
      - Snyder, Donald Paul, 1964 (Box 7)
      - Steele, Arthur, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Tepaske, John, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Turner, Carl, 1965 (Box 7)
      - Wellborn, Charles, 1964 (Box 7)
      - Wikinson, Harold, 1962 (Box 7)
      - Zuber, Richard, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Subcommittee on Matters Relating to the Graduate School
      - Report (Box 7)
      - Travelling Fellowships (Box 7)
      - Subcommittees, minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
    - Graduate Students
      - Donathan, Carl Dale (Box 7)
      - Fox, Judy W. (Box 7)
      - Gruber, Ira (Box 7)
      - Haire, Koleen "Kay" (Box 7)
      - Hilty, Hiram (Box 7)
      - Hofstad, Roger (Box 7)
      - Job Offers (Box 7)
      - Lewis, James (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
      - Morton, Charles (Box 8)
      - Nunn, Charles F. (Box 8)
      - Prichard, Howard (Box 8)
    - Graduate Studies
      - Durden (Box 8)
      - Graduate Studies, Lanning, Inquiries (Box 8)
      - Graduate Studies, Parker (Box 8)
      - Graduate Studies, Tepaske (Box 8)
  - Greene, W.K. (Box 8)
  - Griffin, Charles C. (HAHR) (Box 8)
  - Gross, Paul (Box 8)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 8)
  - H, [2 folders] (Box 8)
  - Hackett, Charles W. (Box 8)
  - Halsema, James (Box 8)
  - Hamilton, Earl J. (Box 8)
  - Hamilton, William B. (Box 8)
  - Hammond, George P. (Box 8)
  - Hanke, Lewis, [2 folders] (Box 8)
  - Hanna, A.J. (Box 8)
  - Hanson, Simon G. (Box 8)
  - Haring, C.H. (Box 8)
  - Hart, Deryl (Box 8)
  - Harvill, Richard A. (Box 8)
  - Harvin, Harry L. (Box 8)
  - Hasbrouck, Alfred (Box 8)
  - Haywood, Wyndham (Box 8)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, [2 folders] (Box 8)
  - Hendon, Bob and Phyllis (Box 8)
  - Herrero, Miguel E. (Box 8)
  - Herring, H.J. (Box 8)
  - Herring, Hubert (Box 8)
  - Hill, Roscoe R. (Box 8)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review, [2 folders] (Box 9)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review (Box 9)
  - History Department
    - General materials, [3 folders] (Box 9)
    - Graduate Applications, 1964 (Box 9)
    - History 128 (Box 9)
    - History 231 (Box 9)
    - History 232 (Box 9)
    - Newsletter (Box 9)
    - Seminar Papers (Box 9)
    - Thesis Topics (Box 9)
    - Vacancies, Latin American (Box 9)
    - History of Ideas in America, First Seminar (Box 9)
  - Hobbs, Marcus (Box 9)
  - Hoffman, Fritz Leo (Box 9)
  - Hollyday (Box 9)
  - Holton, Holland (Box 9)
  - Hoover, Calvin Bryce (Box 9)
  - House (Box 9)
  - Houseknecht, Peter (Box 9)
  - Howard, David (Box 9)
  - Howell, Wilson M. (Box 9)
  - Hussey, Roland Dennis (Box 9)
  - H, Miscellaneous Notes and Papers (Box 9)
  - I (Box 9)
  - I, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 9)
  - IBM Statements (Box 9)
  - Income Tax (Box 9)
  - Internal Revenue Service (Box 9)
  - J, [2 folders] (Box 10)
  - Jackson, Desmond S. (Box 10)
  - James, Concho Romero (Box 10)
  - Jones, C.K. (Box 10)
  - Johnson, John J. (Box 10)
  - Jordan, Charles E. (Box 10)
  - K, [2 folders] (Box 10)
  - Keith, Alan, Lucas Manuscript Publication Committee (Box 10)
  - Kennecott Lectures (Box 10)
  - Kibre, Adele (Box 10)
  - Kiemen, Mathias (Box 10)
  - King, James F., [3 folders] (Box 10)
  - Knight, Douglas M. (Box 10)
  - Knox, Norman (Box 10)
  - Konetzke, Richard, [2 folders] (Box 10)
  - Kyle, Joseph B. (Box 10)
  - L, [3 folders] (Box 10)
  - LaBarge, Richard (Box 10)
  - Lanning, Elizabeth (Box 10)
  - Lanning, J.P. (John Patrick) (Box 10)
  - Personal materials of John Tate Lanning
    - Contributions to Lanning Book Fund, [3 folders] (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and Papers while Editor of Hispanic American Historical Review 1939-44 (Box 10)
    - Critiques; Reviews (Box 10)
    - 1971 Lima Trip (Box 10)
    - Papers, [2 folders] (Box 10)
    - Diary of trip to Europe, 1926-27 (Box 11)
    - Personal-Duke University, [2 folders] (Box 11)
    - Family Matters (Box 11)
    - Honors/Awards/Etc. (Box 11)
    - Mexico (Box 11)
    - Publications (Box 11)
    - Research Council (Box 11)
    - Research Grants, Leaves, Personal Research (Box 11)
    - Vita (Box 11)
  - Lanning, Lacy (Box 11)
  - Lanning, Tate (Box 11)
  - Lanning, Thomas Pickney (Box 11)
  - Laprade, W.T. (Box 11)
  - Lastres, Juan B. (Box 11)
  - Latin-American Conference (Box 11)
  - Latin-American Library Project, [2 folders] (Box 11)
  - Latin-American Persons who should receive free subscriptions (Box 11)
  - Latin American Program (Box 11)
  - Latin Amrican Studies (Box 11)
  - Leal, Ildefonso (Box 11)
  - Learned Societies, Membership Lists (Box 11)
  - Leavitt, Sturgis (Box 11)
  - Lectures, Notes (Box 12)
  - Lecuna, Vicente (Box 12)
  - Leitz, E. (Box 12)
  - Leonard, Irving A., [2 folders] (Box 12)
  - Library Council (Box 12)
  - Library of Congress (Box 12)
  - Lievsay, John L. (Box 12)
  - Lockey, Joseph B. (Box 12)
  - Long-Rang Planning, Subcommittee on for the Graduate School (Box 12)
  - Louisiana State University Press (Box 12)
  - Luvaas, Jay (Box 12)
  - M, [3 folders] (Box 12)
  - M, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 12)
  - Macias, Paper (Box 12)
  - Magallon, Tomas (Box 12)
  - Malagon, Dr. (Box 12)
  - Maltby, William (Box 12)
  - Manchester, Allan K. (Box 12)
  - Manuscript materials, The Eighteenth Century Enlightenment in the University of San Carlos de Guatemala and The University in Kingdom of Guatemala, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Manuscript materials, children's book (Box 12)
  - Marchant, Alexander (Box 12)
  - Markman, Sidney (Box 12)
  - Martin, P.A. (Box 12)
  - Martinez Duran, Carlos (Box 12)
  - Matthews, Robert (Box 12)
  - Medina, Celia (Box 12)
  - Mendez (Box 12)
  - Metraux, Guy S. (Box 12)
  - Mexican Newsletter (Box 13)
  - Microfilm Orders (Box 13)
    RESTRICTED
  - Microfilm Orders, Library of Congress (Box 13)
  - Microfilm Ordered (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 13)
  - Molina, Adolfo (Box 13)
  - Monterde, Francisco (Box 13)
  - Morison, S.E. (Box 13)
  - Munro, Dana (Box 13)
  - Mc, General Correspondence (Box 13)
  - McNicoll, Robert E., [2 folders] (Box 13)
  - N (Box 13)
  - N, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review editor (Box 13)
  - Naranjo, Enrique (Box 13)
  - National Archives (Box 13)
  - National City Bank (Box 13)
  - Nelson, Ernest W. (Box 13)
  - News Items (Box 13)
  - Nichols, Lawrence R. (Box 13)
  - Nichols, Madaline, [2 folders] (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Commission (Box 13)
  - Nowell, Charles E. (Box 13)
  - Nuermberger, Gustave A. (Box 13)
  - O (Box 13)
  - O, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 13)
  - Osborne, Lilly Dejongh (Box 13)
  - Otis, Robert R. (Box 13)
  - Owre, J. Riis (Box 13)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 14)
  - PAB-PHO (Box 14)
  - PIC-POW (Box 14)
  - PRA-PYB (Box 14)
  - P, Correspondence while Editor of Hispanic American Historical Review (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 14)
  - Pacheco, Teresa (Box 14)
  - Pargellis, Stanley (Box 14)
  - Parker, Harold T. (Box 14)
  - Parks, E.T. (Box 14)
  - Parra, Rosario (Box 14)
  - Pattee, Richard (Box 14)
  - Pearse, Arthur S. (Box 14)
  - Pena, Jose de la (Box 14)
  - Personal, Vita (Box 14)
  - Persons interested in Hispanic material (Box 14)
  - Peters, Frank A. (Box 14)
  - Peterson, Harold F. (Box 14)
  - Ph.D's of Duke University (Box 14)
  - PhD. Candidates' Folder (Box 14)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 14)
  - Physioc, John and Willis (Box 14)
  - Piedra, Harry T. (Box 14)
  - Pike, Frederick B. (Box 14)
  - Pine: Role of United State Special Agents in the Development of a Spanish American (Box 14)
  - Policy, 1810-1922 (Box 14)
  - Popescu, Oreste (Box 15)
  - Porto, Jose Gonzalez (Box 15)
  - Powell, Benjamin E. (Box 15)
  - Powell, Philip W. (Box 15)
  - Predmore, Richard (Box 15)
  - Prichard, Howard O. (Box 15)
  - Priestley, Herbert I. (Box 15)
  - Professional Meetings (Box 15)
  - Publications Committee, [2 folders] (Box 15)
  - Publication, Lanning, "University and Learning in the Kingdom of Guatemala" (Box 15)
  - Publications, Lists from American Library Service (Box 15)
  - Publishing Projects (Box 15)
  - Q (Box 15)
  - Qunitanar, Emilio (Box 15)
  - Quirk, Robert (Box 15)
  - Quynn, Dorothy Mackay (Box 15)
  - R, [2 folders] (Box 15)
  - R, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 15)
  - Raup, William (Box 15)
  - Reading Suggestions (Box 15)
  - Recommendations A-Z (Box 15)
  - Reid, John T. (Box 15)
  - Reprint Acknowledgements (Box 15)
  - Reprints and Pamphlets given by authors (Box 15)
  - Reprints, xeroxes of articles (Box 15)
  - Research Council (Box 15)
  - Reyes, Jose Luis (Box 15)
  - Reynolds, Victor (Box 15)
  - Rippy, J. Fred, [2 folders] (Box 15)
  - Robertson, Cora Moore (Box 15)
  - Roberson, James A., [2 folders] (Box 15)
  - Robertson, W.S. (Box 16)
  - Robredo (Box 16)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, [2 folders] (Box 16)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Coordinators Materials (Box 16)
  - Rodriguez, Emilio Demorizi (Box 16)
  - Rodriguez, Mario, Paper (Box 16)
  - Rosenwald Fund (Box 16)
  - Ross, Kip (Box 16)
  - Ross, Stanley (Box 16)
  - Rowe, James Burnett (Box 16)
  - Rudiger, Rudolph (Box 16)
  - Rydjord, John (Box 16)
  - Ryle, Walter H. (Box 16)
  - Rubio Mane, J. I., [3 folders] (Box 16)
  - S, [3 folders] (Box 16)
  - S, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor, [2 folders] (Box 16)
  - Salazar, Gabriel (Box 16)
  - Samayoa, Vincente Diaz (Box 16)
  - Sanchez, Gov. M. (Box 16)
  - Sanford, Terry (Box 16)
  - Savage, Louise (Box 16)
  - Scholes, France (Box 16)
  - Scholes, Walter V. (Box 16)
  - Schuster, Paper (Box 16)
  - Seckinger, Ron Leroy (Box 16)
  - Sensabaugh, Professor (Box 16)
  - Shafer, Boyd C. (Box 16)
  - Sheeler, William (Box 16)
  - Shoaf (Box 16)
  - Shyrock, Richard H. (Box 16)
  - Simpson, Lesley B. (Box 16)
  - Singleton, Marvin K. (Box 16)
  - Skinner-Klee, Jorge (Box 16)
  - Sloan Foundation (Box 16)
  - Sluiter, Engel (Box 16)
  - Smith, Natalie (Box 16)
  - Smith, Robert C. (Box 16)
  - Smith, Robert S. (Box 16)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 16)
  - Snellgrove, Harold (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 16)
  - Sociedad Colombista Panamericana (Box 17)
  - Society of American Historians (Box 17)
  - Society of Colonial Wars (Box 17)
  - Southeastern Institute of Medieval and Renaissance Studies (Box 17)
  - Southeastern Roundtable on Latin American Studies (Box 17)
  - Southern Historical Association, Latin American Section (Box 17)
  - Spalding, Hughes (Box 17)
  - Spanish letters to archivists (Box 17)
  - Spanish Missions of Georgia (Box 17)
  - Spanish Project (Box 17)
  - Spengler, Joseph J. (Box 17)
  - Steck, Francis B. (Box 17)
  - Steele, Arthur (Box 17)
  - Steering Committee Stengerg, R.R. (Box 17)
  - Stephenson, Wendell (Box 17)
  - Sterens, Harry (Box 17)
  - Steward, Truman J. (Box 17)
  - Stewart, Watt (Box 17)
  - Stoan, Stephen K. (Box 17)
  - Stockton, Manly (Box 17)
  - Students, Outstanding (Box 17)
  - Student Unrest, Article by Lanning, "The Mounting Anarchy at Duke", 1968 (Box 17)
  - Student Unrest, Clippings and Photocopies, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - Student Unrest, Correspondence and Printed Material (Box 17)
  - Student Unrest, J.L. Meriam Letter (Box 17)
  - Subscribers to the Hispanic American Historical Review (Box 17)
  - T, [2 folders] (Box 17)
  - T, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 17)
  - Tannenbaum, Frank (Box 17)
  - Tate, Vernon D. (Box 17)
  - Taube, Mortimer (Box 17)
  - Taylor, Orville (Box 17)
  - Thomas, Mary Olive (Box 17)
  - Tepaske, John (Box 17)
  - Tibesar, Antoine (Box 17)
  - Tiempo (Box 17)
  - Tischendorf, A. (Box 17)
  - Torres-Rioseco, Arturo (Box 17)
  - Traveling Fellowships (Box 17)
  - Traveling Fellowships, Reports (Box 17)
  - Tulane-Middle American Research (Box 17)
  - U (Box 18)
  - U, Correspondence while Hispanic American Historical Review Editor (Box 18)